<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>StudyU - Personalized Health Interventions Blog</title>
        <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog</link>
        <description>StudyU - Personalized Health Interventions Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>de</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StudyU beim 2. Frühjahrssymposium für Medizinische Informatik in Heidelberg]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/heidelberg-symposium</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/heidelberg-symposium</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Johannes Vedder präsentiert die StudyU-Plattform beim 2. Frühjahrssymposium für Medizinische Informatik in Heidelberg]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAAIAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQF/8QAIRAAAgICAQQDAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDEQAFBAYHEhQhMUH/xAAUAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAE/8QAGhEAAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIBERIiMf/aAAwDAQACEQMRAD8A19d1lrUnn9zVe5qz5XzmYiqiJKAVRYsAtfnlZyWfuNoY55Ej6J5rorEKwmVbF/dX8Yxg31qhKRl0/9k=&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="1280" height="960"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_symposium.443606e.1280.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_symposium.443606e.1280.jpg 1280w" width="1280" height="960"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">Johannes Vedder präsentiert die StudyU-Plattform beim 2. Frühjahrssymposium
für Medizinische Informatik in Heidelberg</figcaption></figure>
<p>Am 8. Mai 2024 präsentierte Johannes Vedder, leitender Entwickler von StudyU, die StudyU-Plattform
auf dem <a href="https://www.klinikum.uni-heidelberg.de/kliniken-institute/institute/institut-fuer-medizinische-informatik/2-heidelberger-fruehjahrssymposium-medizinische-informatik" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2. Frühjahrssymposium für Medizinische Informatik in Heidelberg</a>, Deutschland.</p>
<p>Das Symposium wurde vom Universitätsklinikum Heidelberg und dem Heidelberger
Institut für Medizinische Informatik, Biometrie und Epidemiologie organisiert und fand in den
Marsilius Arkaden der Universität Heidelberg statt.</p>
<p>Das Symposium wurde von einem vielfältigen Publikum von Experten für medizinische Informatik,
Klinikern und Forschern besucht. Die StudyU-Plattform wurde als neuartiges Werkzeug zur Gestaltung,
Durchführung und Analyse von N-of-1-Studien vorgestellt. Die Präsentation hob das Potenzial der
StudyU-Plattform hervor, die personalisierte Medizin zu revolutionieren, indem sie Forschern
ermöglicht, groß angelegte N-of-1-Studien digital durchzuführen. Darüber hinaus wurden
<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/docs/basics/studies">aktuelle Zusammenarbeiten und laufende Projekte</a>
diskutiert, die die StudyU-Plattform in verschiedenen klinischen Umgebungen nutzen, und zeigten die
Vielseitigkeit und Anwendbarkeit der Plattform in verschiedenen Forschungsbereichen und
internationalen Kontexten auf.</p>
<p>Die Präsentation wurde vom Publikum gut aufgenommen, das Interesse
an den Fähigkeiten und potenziellen Anwendungen der Plattform zeigte. Mehrere Teilnehmer sprachen
Johannes Vedder nach der Präsentation an, um sich über die Plattform zu informieren und mögliche
Zusammenarbeiten zu diskutieren.</p>
<p>Insgesamt war das 2. Heidelberger Frühjahrssymposium für Medizinische Informatik eine erfolgreiche
Veranstaltung, die eine hervorragende Plattform für die Präsentation der StudyU-Plattform und den
Austausch mit der Gemeinschaft der medizinischen Informatik bot. Das positive Feedback, das auf dem
Symposium erhalten wurde, bestätigt weiterhin die Bedeutung und Relevanz der StudyU-Plattform im
Bereich der personalisierten Medizin. Wir freuen uns darauf, die Plattform weiter zu fördern und mit
Forschern und Klinikern zusammenzuarbeiten, um das Feld der N-of-1-Studien und der personalisierten
Medizin voranzutreiben.</p>
<p>Wir möchten uns bei den Organisatoren des Symposiums Prof. Dr. Martin Dugas und Prof. Dr. Petra Knaup-Gregori
für die Möglichkeit, StudyU auf der Veranstaltung zu präsentieren und für die Organisation eines anregenden
anregenden Symposiums bedanken.</p>
<p>Wenn Sie mehr über die StudyU-Plattform erfahren oder mit uns zusammenarbeiten möchten, zögern Sie
bitte nicht, uns <a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/contact">zu kontaktieren</a>.</p>
<p>Bleiben Sie dran für weitere Updates zu StudyU und bevorstehende Veranstaltungen!</p>
<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAAFAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAYH/8QAIhAAAQQBAgcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACAwURBiEEBxIlMUFU/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgP/xAAZEQACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAgEDETH/2gAMAwEAAhEDEQA/AMc4DXeoaxjYI7CSVrNwJT1jb1g5yFTt5wXQaO31Hj5Goiqtr50MH//Z&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="4000" height="1824"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_castle.e4bb5f1.4000.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_castle.e4bb5f1.4000.jpg 4000w" width="4000" height="1824"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">Das Heidelberger Schloss</figcaption></figure>
<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAAFAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQH/8QAIRAAAgAGAQUAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIAAwQFESEGEhMxNNL/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAADBP/EABkRAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACARIxIf/aAAwDAQACEQMRAD8AyGm53emozLZ6ZSFI7iU0oPrHhunR3EjTbkzEm73AknPsTPqEIpSbaC3MP//Z&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="4000" height="1824"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_city.fa2bb29.4000.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/heidelberg_city.fa2bb29.4000.jpg 4000w" width="4000" height="1824"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">Die Stadt Heidelberg</figcaption></figure>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Innovative Anti-Stress Study among Physicians at Charité]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The "Anti-Stress Intervention Among Physicians (ASIP)" Study utilizes]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The "Anti-Stress Intervention Among Physicians (ASIP)" Study utilizes
StudyU to investigate the following intriguing and pertinent research
question:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How can the everyday level of perceived stress be reduced in a fast and
easy-to-implement manner?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The project will be conducted in cooperation with the <a href="https://iph.charite.de/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Institute for Public
Health at Charité</a> – Universitätsmedizin Berlin
(Principal Investigator: Dr. med. Valentin Vetter).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>Physicians in Germany generally experience a high level of psychosocial stress.
This holds true for those working in hospitals, general practitioners, and
physicians in outpatient clinics. It is a well-known fact that high levels of
stress negatively impact the physical and mental health of individuals. In
physicians' case, however, high stress levels have also been identified as a
reason for suboptimal quality of medical care. This includes deviations from
standard procedures, a decrease in the quality of the doctor-patient
relationship, and treatment errors. Potentially substantial structural changes
in the organization and management of health care as well as in the way
physicians are compensated by health insurers would be required to achieve
sustainable improvements for medical personnel. Hence, a more immediate and
easy-to-implement solution to reduce perceived stress is needed.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-intervention">The Intervention<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians#the-intervention" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>An intervention to improve the stress level of physicians must meet certain
criteria to increase the likelihood of being implemented in everyday life and
leading to sustainable improvements. First, the intervention needs to be easy to
learn and brief, as time is often limited during a busy workday. Second, the
intervention should be conducted without additional tools. Third, the
intervention needs to be successful in reducing stress. All the criteria listed
above are fulfilled by two techniques that have been intensively studied over
the past decades: breathwork and mindfulness-based meditation techniques.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-use-an-n-of-1-design">Why Use an N-of-1 Design<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians#why-use-an-n-of-1-design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>Perception of stress is highly individual and dependent on a large number of
variables, both known and unknown, which are partly hard to measure accurately.
The same is potentially true for the effect of an anti-stress intervention on
stress levels. Therefore, a randomized study design is needed to account for all
known and unknown confounders. While randomized placebo-controlled trials (RCTs)
are often used to assess the effects of interventions, this might not be the
ideal design for anti-stress interventions. Firstly, RCTs focus on the outcome
effect on the group level but neglect intra-individual effects. However, for an
anti-stress intervention, it is much more interesting to analyze the effects of
the intervention within the individual (which can differ from between-group
effects). Additionally, population-level effects can subsequently be estimated
from the data collected in the N-of-1 trial as well, thereby ensuring no
insights are lost. Secondly, due to the repeated measurements in an N-of-1
trial, temporal changes can be analyzed. Thirdly, owing to advanced applications
like StudyU, the interventions can be applied, and the outcomes
measured, in the context of daily life. Due to these (and additional)
advantages, N-of-1 trials are "regarded [to be] at the top of the evidence
hierarchy [...] over and above systematic reviews of RCTs" (Kwasnicka et al.,
2019) for individual treatment choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="digital-application-of-intervention-through-studyu">Digital Application of Intervention through StudyU<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/anti-stress-study-among-physicians#digital-application-of-intervention-through-studyu" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>The StudyU platform contributes to the ASIP Study by providing a user-friendly
interface that manages and applies the intervention (through audio/video files)
and collects the participant-reported outcome measures. The application will
ensure good adherence to the study protocol by presenting the current phase of
the trial in a structured and clear way, as well as through push notifications.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StudyU's Role in Easing Antidepressant Discontinuation in the FAB-Study]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the publication of the first research paper utilizing the StudyU platform]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the publication of the first research paper utilizing the StudyU platform
for a medical study. The paper <a href="https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-023-05184-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Study protocol: combined N-of-1 trials to assess open-label placebo treatment for antidepressant discontinuation symptoms [FAB-study]</a>
was published in cooperation with <a href="https://www.hsu-hh.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</a> and <a href="https://www.ukgm.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Universitätsklinikum Giessen und Marburg</a>,
both of them based in Germany.</p>
<p>Let us have a deeper look into the content of this innovative study and what this achievement means for StudyU.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unlocking-the-power-of-n-of-1-trials-with-studyu">Unlocking the Power of N-of-1 Trials with StudyU<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#unlocking-the-power-of-n-of-1-trials-with-studyu" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>StudyU</strong> is a novel platform leading the way in the digital transformation of N-of-1 trials, the gold standard for
assessing personalized treatments. N-of-1 trials compare two interventions for each participant to identify the most
effective one. Comprising the <strong>StudyU Designer</strong> for specifying and publishing trials and the <strong>StudyU App</strong> for
participant engagement, the StudyU platform empowers clinicians and researchers globally to conduct secure digital
N-of-1 trials. <strong>StudyU</strong> envisions a future of more accessible and collaborative personalized treatments, available as
a free research tool and a versatile resource for clinical practice.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="addressing-the-antidepressant-discontinuation-challenge">Addressing the Antidepressant Discontinuation Challenge<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#addressing-the-antidepressant-discontinuation-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>Antidepressant discontinuation is a complex issue, with many individuals facing adverse effects and symptoms that hinder
the process of stopping medication. This can result in unnecessary, long-term use of antidepressants. The FAB-Study
acknowledges this challenge and proposes a solution around the concept of N-of-1 trials, which involves individual
patients using the <strong>StudyU App</strong> to provide personalized insights into their treatment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-fab-study-a-closer-look">The FAB-Study: A Closer Look<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#the-fab-study-a-closer-look" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>The FAB-Study involves conducting a series of randomized, single-blinded N-of-1 trials. In total, 20 patients with fully
remitted DSM-V major depressive disorder, who are experiencing moderate to severe discontinuation symptoms after
stopping antidepressants, participate in the study.</p>
<p>Each N-of-1 trial consists of two cycles, each spanning eight weeks. Within these cycles, patients experience two-week
alternating periods of open-label placebo (OLP) treatment and no treatment, in a randomized order. Their self-reported
discontinuation symptoms are captured twice daily via our smartphone application, <strong>StudyU</strong>. Additionally, the study
tracks their expectations about discontinuation symptoms and mood states.</p>
<p>More information about the study is available in the open access paper: <a href="https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-023-05184-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Study protocol: combined N-of-1 trials to assess open-label placebo treatment for antidepressant discontinuation symptoms [FAB-study]</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-studyu-supported-the-fab-study">How StudyU supported the FAB-Study<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#how-studyu-supported-the-fab-study" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>For the successful execution of a digital N-of-1 study, supportive and patient-friendly tools are essential. Due to the
unique nature of N-of-1 trials and their special requirements, the N-of-trial tailored platform <strong>StudyU</strong> served as a
particularly helpful instrument during the implementation of the FAB-Study:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The new StudyU platform greatly supported the FAB-Study, by serving as an easy-to-use and cost-effective therapeutic
tool for us. Working with StudyU proved to be a pleasant experience for both the researchers and our patients. We will
definitely consider using StudyU for future N-of-1 studies."</p>
<p>-Amke Müller, study director of the first medical study utilizing StudyU</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="promising-potential">Promising Potential<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#promising-potential" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>The results of the FAB-Study may provide valuable insights into the clinical use of open-label placebos for treating
antidepressant discontinuation symptoms. Furthermore, the study not only addresses the clinical challenge at hand but
also investigates the feasibility and applicability of a series of N-of-1 trials in a clinical discontinuation trial.
Such insights could pave the way for more personalized, patient-centric treatments.</p>
<p>As N-of-1 studies become more widespread, digital N-of-1 platforms could play a vital role in the future in supporting
personalized healthcare. They provide the infrastructure needed to streamline the trial process, from specifying
interventions to real-time data collection and analysis. In addition, digital N-of-1 platforms play a key role in the
adoption of N-of-1 studies, as traditional analog methods had limitations in their implementation.</p>
<p>With digital platforms, such as <strong>StudyU</strong>, trials can be conducted remotely or via smartphones, enhancing participant
engagement and ensuring the accuracy and integrity of the data. The scalability and efficiency they offer make N-of-1
trials more accessible and practical for personalized treatment assessment, holding great promise for the future of
healthcare.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>As the developers of the <strong>StudyU</strong> platform, we are pleased to see <strong>StudyU</strong> being actively used in health research.
It makes us proud to see how <strong>StudyU</strong> contributes to an important research topic in the field of antidepressant
discontinuation. The FAB study is an example of the potential of personalized medicine and the central role <strong>StudyU</strong>
can play in this area.</p>
<p>For us, the paper represents a significant step toward enhancing healthcare and improving the lives of patients. We are
excited about the future and the possibilities that personalized healthcare, powered by technologies like <strong>StudyU</strong>, holds.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing StudyU to the German Federal Minister of Health]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/federal-health-minister-meets-studyu</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/federal-health-minister-meets-studyu</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<CaptionWrapper caption="Dr. Stefan Konigorski showcasing the capabilities of StudyU for personalized]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAAHAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUG/8QAIhAAAgIABAcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQMCEQAHEhMFBiFBQmGB/8QAFAEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA//EABsRAAIBBQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAQMREyFR/9oADAMBAAIRAxEAPwC1mHz67gEkRTNMm7rV7M02ZnxN1QA79bNj5klZqAKgGGesACWlEQL9YYYZaKcBytaNn//Z&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="2016" height="1512"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/health_minister.cfa1649.2016.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/health_minister.cfa1649.2016.jpg 2016w" width="2016" height="1512"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">Dr. Stefan Konigorski showcasing the capabilities of StudyU for personalized
healthcare interventions to the German Federal Minister of Health, Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach</figcaption></figure>
<p>On June 8, 2023, we had the honor of introducing StudyU to Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach,
the German Federal Minister of Health, during his visit to the Digital Health Cluster at the
Hasso Plattner Institute (HPI). In a engaging discussion with senior researcher Dr. Stefan Konigorski,
the minister was able to gain firsthand knowledge about how StudyU offers an empowering opportunity
to develop individualized care plans and enhance patient outcomes.</p>
<p>Prof. Lauterbach was already aware of how N-of-1 trials have the potential to provide personalized
insights into treatment effectiveness. However, he was impressed to learn that StudyU enables the
digital conduction of these trials, making them more accessible and convenient. The digital implementation
of N-of-1 trials through StudyU left a lasting positive impression on him, emphasizing the platform's
capability to advance personalized healthcare research.</p>
<p>We want to thank Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach for taking his time to visit the Digital Health Cluster at HPI
to learn more about StudyU and other ongoing digital health research projects.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.studyu.health/de/assets/files/Poster_StudyU-9deab6905db28eca6cd7645957b67b58.pdf" target="_blank">Click here to download our new StudyU poster</a>!</p>
<p>Image credits: Leon Stebe</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StudyU has won the Best Idea Award 2022 at HPI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/best-idea-award</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/best-idea-award</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<CaptionWrapper caption="The winning team StudyU with Pauline Gieseler (middle left) and]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAoAAAAHCAIAAAC+zks0AAAACXBIWXMAADXUAAA11AFeZeUIAAAA4klEQVR4nGPg5OBi5+Tl4xMS4BMVFZMVkVJW1zVW0NRSVdeWV9VlUNfQCzEyi7B2tjZ1DbbzCzW11ZDV8zUw7UhLV1DXZ1CWl3GSlc3TN+iLDGyMDoqytgkxN0+30jfV0lbS0WcQ4+MT5+Fp89ffVBBR5eHoa2FqoCBjpChjr6XSHh/LYK6m6KGh6qEl72+kHW1mkO9s7KAqoyMpsryu+vX2EwxZtuETgr081ZVEOLls5SXq7FXijNWrwwKPzZ50d+VshnhDyxoX/Qg9GUtpIS8V8S4n2e5g84bI0DXxBlvjNAEppzUWqtf/XQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="1030" height="687"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award.88bc93e.1030.png" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award.88bc93e.1030.png 1030w" alt="" width="1030" height="687"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">The winning team StudyU with Pauline Gieseler (middle left) and
Johannes Vedder (middle right)</figcaption></figure>
<p>StudyU has won the <b>Best Idea Award 2022</b> of the School Of Entrepreneurship at Hasso Plattner
Institute (HPI). The team consists of Pauline Gieseler and Johannes Vedder, who are both
students at the Hasso Plattner Institute in Potsdam, Germany.</p>
<p>Winning this award grants us the opportunity to <b>visit HPI New York City</b> and meet its director,
Dr. Joann Halpern. Additionally, it enables us to establish connections with HPI･MS, a collaborative
project between HPI and <a href="https://www.mountsinai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mount Sinai Health System</a>, renowned as one
of the world's top-ranked hospitals.</p>
<p>With these new possibilities, our goal is to further enhance the development of StudyU, so that a
greater number of individuals will be able to experience the advantages of personalized healthcare
interventions.</p>
<p>Many thanks to everyone who voted for us!</p>
<p>Read more on the HPI website: <a href="https://hpi.de/entrepreneurship/best-idea.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://hpi.de/entrepreneurship/best-idea.html</a>.</p>
<p>Image credits: HPI School Of Entrepreneurship</p>
<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAoAAAAFCAYAAAB8ZH1oAAAACXBIWXMAABYlAAAWJQFJUiTwAAAA2ElEQVR4nAHNADL/ALqKTvq5h1f/sHxS/82wjf/h1cH/07qn/9i+rP+6opX+1uHp/9HX2+kAd2BK+ltINv99YUr/vIll/86xnf+/mIH/u66h/1BPVf6mrbX//fz76QB5cGn6VkY7/4RWO/+lWUD/gWRY/zNIS/9ASE//Dxsw/mZxgP/////pAKKUg/pXRjn/snhC/35xaf9ZTEX/ABco/w8WI/8qLTf+SFNl/9jo8OkAd2xe+mVLOf9sUDn/TExN/1FGQ/8DGyr/Q0A//4xqTv6Pgnz/nbjP6bGteJI30lmvAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="584" height="320"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award_3.b133ef0.584.png" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award_3.b133ef0.584.png 584w" width="584" height="320"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">The winning team (Johannes Vedder, Pauline Gieseler and Dr. Stefan Konigorski (right) together with Dr. Joann Halpern, the Director of the Hasso Plattner Institute, New York (second from the right)</figcaption></figure>
<div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAANAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABQQI/8QAIxAAAgECBgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDBCEABQYRIkETURKBkf/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAID/8QAHBEAAgICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIAAwQFESKR/9oADAMBAAIRAxEAPwBzMNa5K1fLKIKOpWTmJEqAfIT6ve/rvFQ1ZR7D45ACOuZxnGaOaTw0q1BRGIRdlsov19nCT6XmR2VM0lCg7Dh1+4k+xNHCWOR7CMKt+yqJ/9k=&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="960" height="1280"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award_2.4a311c0.960.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award_2.4a311c0.960.jpg 960w" width="960" height="1280"></noscript></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>