<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>StudyU - Personalized Health Interventions Blog</title>
        <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog</link>
        <description>StudyU - Personalized Health Interventions Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>de</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StudyU's Role in Easing Antidepressant Discontinuation in the FAB-Study]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/studyu-fab-study-antidepressant-discontinuation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the publication of the first research paper utilizing the StudyU platform]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce the publication of the first research paper utilizing the StudyU platform
for a medical study. The paper <a href="https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-023-05184-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Study protocol: combined N-of-1 trials to assess open-label placebo treatment for antidepressant discontinuation symptoms [FAB-study]</a>
was published in cooperation with <a href="https://www.hsu-hh.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</a> and <a href="https://www.ukgm.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Universitätsklinikum Giessen und Marburg</a>,
both of them based in Germany.</p>
<p>Let us have a deeper look into the content of this innovative study and what this achievement means for StudyU.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unlocking-the-power-of-n-of-1-trials-with-studyu">Unlocking the Power of N-of-1 Trials with StudyU<a href="#unlocking-the-power-of-n-of-1-trials-with-studyu" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>StudyU</strong> is a novel platform leading the way in the digital transformation of N-of-1 trials, the gold standard for
assessing personalized treatments. N-of-1 trials compare two interventions for each participant to identify the most
effective one. Comprising the <strong>StudyU Designer</strong> for specifying and publishing trials and the <strong>StudyU App</strong> for
participant engagement, the StudyU platform empowers clinicians and researchers globally to conduct secure digital
N-of-1 trials. <strong>StudyU</strong> envisions a future of more accessible and collaborative personalized treatments, available as
a free research tool and a versatile resource for clinical practice.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="addressing-the-antidepressant-discontinuation-challenge">Addressing the Antidepressant Discontinuation Challenge<a href="#addressing-the-antidepressant-discontinuation-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>Antidepressant discontinuation is a complex issue, with many individuals facing adverse effects and symptoms that hinder
the process of stopping medication. This can result in unnecessary, long-term use of antidepressants. The FAB-Study
acknowledges this challenge and proposes a solution around the concept of N-of-1 trials, which involves individual
patients using the <strong>StudyU App</strong> to provide personalized insights into their treatment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-fab-study-a-closer-look">The FAB-Study: A Closer Look<a href="#the-fab-study-a-closer-look" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>The FAB-Study involves conducting a series of randomized, single-blinded N-of-1 trials. In total, 20 patients with fully
remitted DSM-V major depressive disorder, who are experiencing moderate to severe discontinuation symptoms after
stopping antidepressants, participate in the study.</p>
<p>Each N-of-1 trial consists of two cycles, each spanning eight weeks. Within these cycles, patients experience two-week
alternating periods of open-label placebo (OLP) treatment and no treatment, in a randomized order. Their self-reported
discontinuation symptoms are captured twice daily via our smartphone application, <strong>StudyU</strong>. Additionally, the study
tracks their expectations about discontinuation symptoms and mood states.</p>
<p>More information about the study is available in the open access paper: <a href="https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-023-05184-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Study protocol: combined N-of-1 trials to assess open-label placebo treatment for antidepressant discontinuation symptoms [FAB-study]</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-studyu-supported-the-fab-study">How StudyU supported the FAB-Study<a href="#how-studyu-supported-the-fab-study" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>For the successful execution of a digital N-of-1 study, supportive and patient-friendly tools are essential. Due to the
unique nature of N-of-1 trials and their special requirements, the N-of-trial tailored platform <strong>StudyU</strong> served as a
particularly helpful instrument during the implementation of the FAB-Study.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="promising-potential">Promising Potential<a href="#promising-potential" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>The results of the FAB-Study may provide valuable insights into the clinical use of open-label placebos for treating
antidepressant discontinuation symptoms. Furthermore, the study not only addresses the clinical challenge at hand but
also investigates the feasibility and applicability of a series of N-of-1 trials in a clinical discontinuation trial.
Such insights could pave the way for more personalized, patient-centric treatments.</p>
<p>As N-of-1 studies become more widespread, digital N-of-1 platforms could play a vital role in the future in supporting
personalized healthcare. They provide the infrastructure needed to streamline the trial process, from specifying
interventions to real-time data collection and analysis. In addition, digital N-of-1 platforms play a key role in the
adoption of N-of-1 studies, as traditional analog methods had limitations in their implementation.</p>
<p>With digital platforms, such as <strong>StudyU</strong>, trials can be conducted remotely or via smartphones, enhancing participant
engagement and ensuring the accuracy and integrity of the data. The scalability and efficiency they offer make N-of-1
trials more accessible and practical for personalized treatment assessment, holding great promise for the future of
healthcare.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Überschrift" title="Direkter Link zur Überschrift">​</a></h2>
<p>As the developers of the <strong>StudyU</strong> platform, we are pleased to see <strong>StudyU</strong> being actively used in health research.
It makes us proud to see how <strong>StudyU</strong> contributes to an important research topic in the field of antidepressant
discontinuation. The FAB study is an example of the potential of personalized medicine and the central role <strong>StudyU</strong>
can play in this area.</p>
<p>For us, the paper represents a significant step toward enhancing healthcare and improving the lives of patients. We are
excited about the future and the possibilities that personalized healthcare, powered by technologies like <strong>StudyU</strong>, holds.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing StudyU to the German Federal Minister of Health]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/federal-health-minister-meets-studyu</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/federal-health-minister-meets-studyu</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On June 8, 2023, we had the honor of introducing StudyU to Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On June 8, 2023, we had the honor of introducing StudyU to Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach,
the German Federal Minister of Health, during his visit to the Digital Health Cluster at the
Hasso Plattner Institute (HPI). In a engaging discussion with senior researcher Dr. Stefan Konigorski,
the minister was able to gain firsthand knowledge about how StudyU offers an empowering opportunity
to develop individualized care plans and enhance patient outcomes.</p>
<p>Prof. Lauterbach was already aware of how N-of-1 trials have the potential to provide personalized
insights into treatment effectiveness. However, he was impressed to learn that StudyU enables the
digital conduction of these trials, making them more accessible and convenient. The digital implementation
of N-of-1 trials through StudyU left a lasting positive impression on him, emphasizing the platform's
capability to advance personalized healthcare research.</p>
<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDAAYEBQYFBAYGBQYHBwYIChAKCgkJChQODwwQFxQYGBcUFhYaHSUfGhsjHBYWICwgIyYnKSopGR8tMC0oMCUoKSj/2wBDAQcHBwoIChMKChMoGhYaKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCgoKCj/wAARCAAHAAoDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUG/8QAIhAAAgIABAcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQMCEQAHEhMFBiFBQmGB/8QAFAEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA//EABsRAAIBBQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAQMREyFR/9oADAMBAAIRAxEAPwC1mHz67gEkRTNMm7rV7M02ZnxN1QA79bNj5klZqAKgGGesACWlEQL9YYYZaKcBytaNn//Z&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="2016" height="1512"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/health_minister.cfa1649.2016.jpg" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/health_minister.cfa1649.2016.jpg 2016w" width="2016" height="1512"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">Dr. Stefan Konigorski showcasing the capabilities of StudyU for personalized
healthcare interventions to the German Federal Minister of Health, Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach</figcaption></figure>
<p>Image credits: Leon Stebe</p>
<p>We want to thank Prof. Dr. Karl Lauterbach for taking his time to visit the Digital Health Cluster at HPI
to learn more about StudyU and other ongoing digital health research projects.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="/de/assets/files/Poster_StudyU-9deab6905db28eca6cd7645957b67b58.pdf">Click here to download our new StudyU poster</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StudyU has won the Best Idea Award 2022 at HPI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/best-idea-award</link>
            <guid>https://www.studyu.health/de/blog/best-idea-award</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are honored to announce that StudyU has won the Best Idea Award 2022 of the School Of Entrepreneurship at]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are honored to announce that StudyU has won the <b>Best Idea Award 2022</b> of the School Of Entrepreneurship at
Hasso Plattner Institute (HPI).</p>
<p>Winning this award grants us the opportunity to <b>visit HPI New York City</b> and meet its director,
Dr. Joann Halpern. Additionally, it enables us to establish connections with HPI･MS, a collaborative
project between HPI and <a href="https://www.mountsinai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mount Sinai Health System</a>, renowned as one of the world's top-ranked hospitals.</p>
<p>With these new possibilities, our goal is to further enhance the development of StudyU, so that a
greater number of individuals will be able to experience the advantages of personalized healthcare interventions.</p>
<p>Many thanks to everyone who voted for us!</p>
<p>Read more on the HPI website: <a href="https://hpi.de/entrepreneurship/best-idea.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://hpi.de/entrepreneurship/best-idea.html</a>.</p>
<figure><div style="background-size:cover;background-repeat:no-repeat;position:relative;background-image:url(&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAoAAAAHCAIAAAC+zks0AAAACXBIWXMAADXUAAA11AFeZeUIAAAA4klEQVR4nGPg5OBi5+Tl4xMS4BMVFZMVkVJW1zVW0NRSVdeWV9VlUNfQCzEyi7B2tjZ1DbbzCzW11ZDV8zUw7UhLV1DXZ1CWl3GSlc3TN+iLDGyMDoqytgkxN0+30jfV0lbS0WcQ4+MT5+Fp89ffVBBR5eHoa2FqoCBjpChjr6XSHh/LYK6m6KGh6qEl72+kHW1mkO9s7KAqoyMpsryu+vX2EwxZtuETgr081ZVEOLls5SXq7FXijNWrwwKPzZ50d+VshnhDyxoX/Qg9GUtpIS8V8S4n2e5g84bI0DXxBlvjNAEppzUWqtf/XQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&quot;)"><svg style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px" width="1030" height="687"></svg><noscript><img style="width:100%;height:auto;max-width:100%;margin-bottom:-4px;position:absolute;top:0;left:0" src="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award.88bc93e.1030.png" srcset="/de/assets/ideal-img/best_idea_award.88bc93e.1030.png 1030w" alt="" width="1030" height="687"></noscript></div><figcaption class="figcaption_pIkn">The winning team StudyU with Pauline Gieseler und Johannes Vedder (middle)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Image credits: HPI School Of Entrepreneurship</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>